<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
#
# Logbook - Add-on for FlightGear
#
# Written and developer by Roman Ludwicki (PlayeRom, SP-ROM)
#
# Copyright (C) 2022 Roman Ludwicki
#
# Logbook is an Open Source project and it is licensed
# under the GNU Public License v3 (GPLv3)
#
-->

<PropertyList>
    <addons>
        <by-id>
            <org.flightgear.addons.logbook>
                <addon-devel>
                    <save>
                        <settings>
                            <dark-style type="bool">0</dark-style>
                        </settings>
                    </save>

                    <!-- This flag is set on true after edit logbook. Then listener is triggered and reload the logbook data.-->
                    <reload-logbook type="bool">false</reload-logbook>

                    <!-- This flag indicate that user removed entry log -->
                    <logbook-entry-deleted type="bool">false</logbook-entry-deleted>

                    <help-text type="string">
This add-on automatically keeps a log of your flights, saving each flight to a CSV file. It does not require any interference, just add an add-on to FlightGear.

You will find the CSV file in the `$FG_HOME/Export/Addons/org.flightgear.addons.logbook/logbook-v%s.csv` directory, where `$FG_HOME` on Windows is:

`C:\Users\{user name}\AppData\Roaming\flightgear.org\`

and on Linux/MacOS:

`/home/{user name}/.fgfs/`

The following information is logged into the file:

1. Date - aircraft take-off date. This is the date taken from your OS, not the date in the simulator. I decided I'd know when I flew in my own time zone, in front of my own computer, rather than what the UTC or local time was in the simulation, which would not be valuable. If you have a different opinion and reasonable arguments, let me know.
2. Time - aircraft take-off time. As for Date this is the time taken from the OS.
3. Aircraft - the code name of the aircraft.
4. Callsign - your callsign set for multiplayer.
5. From - the ICAO code of the airport from which you have taken off. If you are starting immediately in the air, this field will remain blank.
6. To - the ICAO code of the airport where you landed. If you did not land (e.g. by closing FG in flight) or by landing at an adventurous location, this field will remain blank.
7. Landings - number of landings made. If you landed anywhere, a 1 will be entered here. If the flight ended without landing or the add-on was unable to detect a valid landing, a 0 will be entered here.
8. Day - the number of hours spent flying during the day.
9. Night - number of hours spent flying during the night.
10. Instrument - the number of hours flown during the IMC (Instrument Meteorological Conditions).
11. Duration - total duration of the flight in hours, as the sum of Day and Night. The instrument is not added up here, as it is simply counted separately, regardless of whether it was day or night.
12. Distance - total distance flown from take-off to landing, in nautical miles.
13. Fuel - total fuel burned, in US gallons.
14. Max Alt - maximum altitude, in feet, reached during flight.
15. Note - notes, by default the full name of the aircraft.

NOTE

1. If you properly close the simulator during the flight ("File" -> "Exit"), the current flight status will be saved to the logbook (without landing information, of course).
2. If the simulator will be closed incorrectly during flight, e.g. via the [X] button on the window bar, or a crash occurs, the flight status will lost.
3. For the add-on to count as a landing, the aircraft must rest on all wheels and maintain this state for at least 3 seconds. In this way, an ugly bounce off the runway will not be counted as a landing.
4. If you start a simulation in the air, the add-on will recognize this and start logging without waiting for take-off.
5. If you start a simulation in the air, the add-on is unable to recognize the landing gear, so the landing pass will extend to 6 seconds (giving an extra 3 seconds to make sure the aircraft is resting on all wheels).
6. Helicopters should also be supported, although I have not tested all of them.
7. The add-on supports JSBSim-based watercraft, although I have not tested all of them.
8. The add-on supports the Space Shuttle.
9. Flights with UFO will not be logged.
10. Pausing the simulation or turning on the replay mode stops the flight statistics from being added to the log.
11. As for fuel burn, the add-on does not take into account the change in the amount of fuel during the flight. When you change the amount of fuel during the flight, the result in the Fuel column will be incorrect. So try to avoid it and refuel the aircraft before the flight.
12. Supported FG versions from 2020.1.
                    </help-text>
                </addon-devel>
            </org.flightgear.addons.logbook>
        </by-id>
    </addons>
</PropertyList>
